Hugo Costa

3308 Overcreek Ln, Midlothian, VA 23112-4522 Gohucosta23@hotmail.com (804) 475-2712

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer, creative problem solver and teamplayer, with experience in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, Database Theory, MongoDB, MySQL, Command Line and Git. Being a software engineer and learning new technologies is my passion. In a previous career, I worked in the financial industry in a sales team, which prepared me to work in a fast paced environment. With over 17 years of experience I will bring outstanding teamwork and leadership skills to my next team.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Small Business Owner, Got Cleaning. Richmond, VA

Nov. 2013 - Present

- Communicating with clients, deepening relationships creating more opportunities and from there generating more business.
- Leading a team of employees to overcome challenges and achieve goals.
- Acquire, distribute and store supplies.

Small Business Sales Consultant, Bank of America Merchant Services Richmond, VA

Mar. 2013 - Nov. 2013

- Network within communities and partners to find and attract new business.
- Work with a sales team to overcome challenges and meet the banking center's sales goal.
- Conduct meetings with partners to explain policies and operating procedures to ensure functional effectiveness of business.
- Develop prospects from current commercial customers, referral leads or sales.
- Prepare forms or agreements to complete sales.

Personal Banker, Bank of America. Richmond, VA

Jan. 2009 – Mar. 2013

- Work with clients to identify their financial goals and to find ways of reaching those goals.
- Work with a sales team to overcome challenges and meet the banking center's sales goal.
- Market bank products to individuals and firms, promoting bank services that may meet customers' needs.
- Explain to customers the different types of loans and credit options that are available, as well as the terms of those services.
- Handle customer complaints and take appropriate action to resolve them.
- Confer with customers by telephone or in person to provide information about products or services, cancel accounts, or obtain details of complaints.

Sales and Service Specialist, Bank of America. Richmond, VA

Jan. 2003 – Jan. 2009

- Work with clients to identify their financial goals and to find ways of reaching those goals.
- Work with a sales team to overcome challenges and meet the banking center's sales goal.
- Handle customer complaints and take appropriate action to resolve them.
- Receive payment by cash, check, credit cards, vouchers, or automatic debits.
- Issue receipts, refunds, credits, or change due to customers.
- Answer customers' questions, and provide information on procedures or policies.

EDUCATION

- 2003-2004 Southwestern Adventist University Computer Science
- 1997-2000 Escola Tecnica de Comercio Candido Mendes (Brazil)
 Commercial Technical High School
 Computer Science

AWARDS

- Top regional sales person for 2 quarters in a row in 2012
- Top regional sales person in Winter 2013

SKILLS

- Fluent in Portuguese/ Spanish
- Building relationships with partners
- Accuracy and attention to detail
- Good Team Player
- Problem solver
- Quick learner